你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府以为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第二季 第四集
音频拦截
会话分析
语言识别
想当年  人们懂得
Back in the day, people understood things like
何谓尊重  何谓忠诚  何为荣誉
respect, loyalty, honor.
今非昔比了
Those days are gone.
你想怎么样
So what do you want to do?
只有一条路  搞定它
Only one thing to do. Take care of it.
发现目标了吗  里瑟先生
Have you located our quarry, Mr. Reese?
找到了
I have.
这地方叫格兰德
At a place called Grand.
好地方
Good choice.
你知道这里
You know it?
翻新后就没再去了
Haven't been back since they renovated,
不过以前的格兰德供应肋眼牛排
but the old Grand served one mean rib eye.
这么说我们的目标有相当昂贵的品味
So our guy has expensive taste, huh?
他老板确实有
The man he works for certainly does.
乔治・梅西在当地颇有几家企业
George Massey owns several local establishments,
不过他更有名的是声誉不怎么好的公司
but he's better known for his less reputable enterprises,
包括放高利贷  洗钱  敲诈勒索
including loan sharking, money laundering, extortion.
真高兴原来爱尔兰黑帮还活蹦乱跳的
Good to know the Irish mob is still alive and kicking.
既然城里要有黑社会
I suppose if the city's gonna have organized criminals,
至少应该多样化
they should at least be diverse.
梅西跟他儿子埃迪共同经营
Massey runs his businesses with his son Eddie.
我们的目标呢
And our guy?
莱利・卡瓦诺
Riley Cavanaugh.
没有亲人  未接受过高等教育
No living family and no education past high school.
似乎他唯一的工作是
The only job he seems to have held
为梅西的一家公司当卡车司机
is driving a truck for a company owned by Massey.
看起来为梅西工作好多年了
Appears to have been an associate of Massey's for several years.
什么工作
What kind of associate?
能引起机器注意的工作
The kind that gets the attention of the machine.
我要进去了
I'm going in.
-有事吗  -有
- Something happening? - Yeah.
吃午餐
Lunch.
跟35街新酒吧的主人谈过了没
Did you talk to the owner of that new bar on 35th?
我们今天晚些时候会去拜访一下
We were gonna drop by later today.
很好  需要我出面就说一声
Good. Let me know if I need to get involved.
莱利・卡瓦诺
强制配对
完成
这是干嘛
What's this?
想抢我的饭碗吗
Trying to take my job?
抱歉  你刚才在忙
Sorry. You looked busy.
你的服务员马上就来
Your server will be with you shortly.
除非你也想抢他的饭碗
Unless you want his job too.
抢了你的就够了
Yours will do for now.
午餐如何  乔治  还满意吗
How's your lunch, George? Everything okay?
阿里  非常棒
Al, it's great.
我几乎都不记得之前的老样子了
I can't even remember what the old place looks like.
街坊都变了
Neighborhood's changed.
就像大家说的  得与时俱进
Have to keep up with the times, as they say.
是啊  有些事变了
Yeah, some things do change.
但也有些没变
But some don't.
比如说  你和我
For instance, you and me.
我知道我拖延了  乔治  但只要给我
I know I'm behind, George, but just give me--
拖延了
Behind?
你可不只是拖延了
You're a little more than behind.
我们为了翻新停业了三个月
We were down for three months with the remodel,
大家也不像之前那样常外出用餐了
and people aren't going out to eat like they used to.
是啊  我知道  我知道
Yeah, I know. I know.
这么说吧
Well, here's the thing.
你尽可以把钱全用于精致的装修
You can spend all your money on your fancy fixtures
和漂亮的墙纸
and your wallpaper
前提是我的钱先付清
as long as you keep paper in my pocket.
明白吗
Understand?
是的
Yeah.
是的  我明白
Yeah, I understand.
很好
Good.
因为下次
Because, uh, next time...
来拜访的人就不会是我了
I'm not gonna be the one who's stopping by.
会是我
It'll be me.
我来可不会是为吃午餐
And I won't be here for lunch.
看来这位的工作是梅西的执刑人
Looks like our associate is Massey's enforcer.
所谓"执刑人"  是说他是行凶者
And by "enforcer", you mean he's our perpetrator?
安妮  别走
Annie, hang on.
过来一下
Come here. Hey.
怎么了  也不跟我们打声招呼
What's going on? You don't say hello anymore?
抱歉  乔治  我有点忙
Sorry, George, I'm kind of busy.
我最近常想到你
You know, I've been thinking a lot about you lately.
是吗  我应该受宠若惊  还是惊恐失措
Yeah? Should I be flattered or scared?
得了
Come on.
我只是想知道你最近如何
I just wanna know how you're doing. You know?
有没有找到人
Whether or not you've found somebody
陪你度过漫漫寒夜
to fend off those cold nights yet.
怎么了  你想毛遂自荐吗  乔治
Why? You offering, George?
我现在还真惊恐失措了
'cause now I'm really scared.
我可是已婚男人  你得放尊重点噢
Hey, I'm a married man. You gotta be more respectful.
而我是你手下的遗孀  这点别忘了
And I'm the widow of one of your guys, in case you forgot,
所以也请你放尊重点  乔治
so back at ya, George.
肖恩的事是场悲剧
What happened to Sean was tragic.
但跟俄罗斯人纠缠的是他  不是我
But he's the one that made his bed with the Russians, not me.
我还以为他是为你工作呢  乔治
I thought he worked for you, George.
是的  但他自己的债是自己的事
Yeah, but his debts were his own.
他是个堕落的赌鬼  所以才会被杀
He was a degenerate gambler, and it got him killed.
你最好学会接受这点  安妮
You had better learn to accept that, Annie.
我接受  我同时还记得
I do, but I also remember
肖恩曾是全世界最好的人
that Sean was the sweetest guy in the world
直到他开始为你工作
until the day he started working for you.
所以无论他是否堕落  我会永远想念他
So degenerate or not, I'll always miss him.
不知道你走之后  谁会想念你呢  乔治
I wonder who's gonna miss you when you're gone, George.
保重  安妮
You take care, Annie.
我们离开这破地方
Let's get the hell outta this dump.
那位年轻姑娘到底是谁啊
And who on earth was that young lady?
服务员
The hostess.
性子颇烈
Got some brass.
刚恶心了乔治一顿
Just served George more than his lunch.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：Nonopig  紫玉  二摆舞  丢丢曳  大黑  天朝直属
时间轴：烟幕迟迟   擦擦
特效&后期：MythCreator   校对&总监：阿好
给我五分钟
Give me five minutes.
他们很小心
They're cautious.
先把手机留到了吧台
They check their phones at the bar
然后才到后边谈
before talking business in the back.
其实  这倒方便我们了
Actually, that may help us.
手机都放到了一起
If the phones are close together,
我就可以利用莱利的手机当宿主机
I can use Riley's as a host...
强制配对成功
联上其他人的
to get up on the other ones.
还是需要听到后边办公室的声音
Still need ears in that back office.
你有何良策
What do you suggest?
随机应变
Improvising.
你他妈哪儿不正常
Hey, what the hell is wrong with you?
现在吗  你脸上的表情呗
Right now, that look on your face.
再喝一杯  聊解千愁
Nothing another drink won't fix.
把他轰出去
Get him outta here.
成功了吗  里瑟先生
Were you successful, Mr. Reese?
马上就知道了
I'll know in a minute.
安妮这事
This thing with Annie.
-算了老爸  -算了
- Forget about it, pop. - Forget about it?
你听到她今天跟我说话的口气了
You heard the way she spoke to me today.
大庭广众之下跟我提她那个二货亡夫
Bringing up that idiot husband of hers in public.
过去人们知道何谓尊重
Used to be people had some respect.
其中一点就是要知道几时该闭嘴
Part of that was knowing when to keep your mouth shut.
也许我该去拜访一下她
Maybe I should pay her a visit.
为什么
Why?
你有什么特别的办法搞定她吗
You got some special way of getting through to her?
我可以告诉她放弃纠结这事
I can tell her to drop the subject.
她看上去像是会放弃的人吗
Does she look like the type who would drop anything?
说不准啊  老爸  莱利挺有说服力的
I don't know, pop, Riley can be pretty persuasive.
好吧
Okay.
你过去  今晚去找她
You go up there. See her tonight.
好的
Okay.
但不是让她闭嘴
But not to shut her up.
而是让她彻底消失
To make her disappear.
我不确定  老大
I don't know, boss.
不确定
Don't know?
不确定什么
Don't know what?
她是自己人的遗孀
She's the widow of one of the boys.
可能会有损士气
Might hurt morale.
士气
Morale?
你是在担心谁的士气
Whose morale are you worried about?
他们的
Theirs?
还是我的
Or mine?
好的  老大
Okay, boss.
我来搞定
I'll take care of it.
好  看你的了
Okay. See that you do.
带上埃迪
Take Eddie.
用珍珠那儿
Use the Pearl.
别留下痕迹
Don't leave a trace.
芬奇  那位执刑人
Finch, our enforcer
要去追杀餐厅里那姑娘了
is going after the girl from the restaurant.
那名服务员  安妮
The hostess? Annie?
她刚成为他的下一个目标
She just became his next target,
而他也成了我的目标
and he just became mine.
里斯先生  我应该不需要提醒你
Mr. Reese, I assume I don't need to remind you
你跟的是危险分子
these are dangerous men you're following.
我已经做好了预防措施  芬奇
I've taken all precautions, Finch.
你找到安妮的信息了吗
You find anything on Annie?
是的  她的全名是安妮・德莱尼
Yes, her name is Anne Delaney,
在布鲁克林出生长大
born and raised in Brooklyn.
她九个月前丧夫  她丈夫肖恩・德莱尼
She was widowed nine months ago when her husband Sean Delaney
在布莱顿海滩被射杀
was found shot to death in Brighton Beach.
那里当时是俄罗斯人的地盘
That was Russian territory then
后来才被以利亚接管
before Elias took it all over.
乔治的手下可不应该去那种地方
Not the place to be if you're one of George's crew.
你有她的地址吗
You have an address for her?
东39街 1424号
1424 EAST 39th.
你正在朝那个方向去
You're headed in that direction.
你想怎么做
So how do you want to do this?
悄悄做
Quietly.
是啊  但怎么做呢  老头子说要没有痕迹
Yeah, but how? The old man said no trace.
我会处理的
I'll handle it.
你帮我望风  准备好处理尸体就行
You just keep an eye out and be ready to help with the body.
你听到了吗  里瑟先生
Are you hearing this, Mr. Reese?
别担心  芬奇
Don't worry, Finch.
我保证他们无法接近她
I'll make sure they don't get anywhere near her.
有人给莱利打电话
Someone's calling Riley.
不  是乔治给埃迪打电话
No, it's George calling Eddie.
-喂  -别说话  听着就行
- Yeah? - Don't talk, just listen.
你今晚动手以前
Before you do that thing tonight,
先处理我们提过的另外那件事
I want you to handle that other business that we talked about.
-莱利  -你确定
- Riley. - You sure?
你今天听到他说的了  埃迪
You heard him today, Eddie.
我给他机会坦白交待了  但他没有
I gave him a chance to come clean, he didn't take it.
我没法再信任他了
I can't trust him anymore.
他只能消失
So he goes.
然后是那姑娘
Then the girl.
你能处理好吗  还是要我亲自处理
Now can you handle this, or do I need to?
不不  我明白
No, no. I got it.
很好  搞定给我电话
Good. Call me when it's done.
怎么了
What's up?
没什么  老头子打电话查岗
Nothing, the old man was just checking in.
你知道他的
You know how he gets.
是啊  我知道
Yeah, I do.
我们可能搞错了  芬奇
We may have this one wrong, Finch.
也许莱利才是受害人
Riley might be the victim after all,
不过可能已经晚了
but I think I'm too late.
晚了
Too late?
什么意思  里瑟先生
What do you mean, Mr. Reese?
怎么回事
What was that?
等等  芬奇
Hang on, Finch.
里瑟先生  他在打电话给安妮
Mr. Reese, he's calling Annie.
喂
Hello?
是我
Hey, it's me.
你还好吗  你听上去很紧张
You okay? You sound stressed.
我很好  安妮  听着
I'm fine. Annie, listen.
出事了
Something's gone wrong.
乔治  他肯定发现了我们的事
George--he must have found out about you and me.
什么  你确定吗
What? Are you sure?
是的  非常确定
Yeah. Pretty sure.
我刚才不得不杀了埃迪
I just had to kill Eddie.
上帝
Oh, my God.
安妮  没事的
Annie, it's gonna be all right.
没事  你刚杀了乔治・梅西的儿子
All right? You just killed George Massey's son.
听着  安妮
Just listen, Annie.
拜托  去我们的地方等着
Please, just go to our place and wait.
我先去个地方  然后就去找你
I'm gonna make a quick stop, and then I'll be there.
好吗
Okay?
安妮
Annie.
好的
Okay.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我刚才没听错吧
Did I just hear that right?
那位执刑人居然爱上了他要杀的女人
Our enforcer is in love with the woman he was sent to kill?
没错
Yeah.
就是说我们要保护两个人了  芬奇
Which means we now have two people to protect, Finch.
里瑟先生  莱利和安妮碰面了吗
Mr. Reese, has Riley met up with Annie yet?
还没
Not yet.
肯定有别的办法找到她
There must be some other way to locate her.
也许  但乔治肯定会派人追杀他们俩
Maybe, but George will be gunning for both of them.
没错  但安妮是其中的无辜受害人
Yes, but Annie is the innocent victim in this equation.
你是说我们只保护安妮  不管莱利吗
Are you saying we should protect Annie but not Riley?
我只是说不值得让你和安妮冒风险
I'm just saying you might not want to put yourself and her
去保护他那种人
at risk for a man like that.
他是个杀手  里瑟先生
He's a killer, Mr. Reese.
我也曾是  芬奇
So was I, Finch.
我认为你们之间区别很明显
I think there's a distinction to be made.
没你想得那么明显
Not as much as you think.
他身陷绝境  时日无多
Well, he's a desperate man running out of time,
乔治不是唯一追他的人
and George won't be the only one after him.
警察也会开始寻找杀害埃迪的凶手
The police will be looking for Eddie's killer as well.
看来得让我们两位警探开始干活了
Guess it's time to put our two detectives to work.
-我是卡特  -早上好  警探
- Carter. - Morning, Detective.
不行  先等我喝完早晨咖啡再说
No, not until I've had my morning coffee.
-你可以随身拿着  -拿去哪里
- You can take it with you. - Take it where?
我把地址发给你
I'm sending you the location.
为什么  那里有什么
Why? What's there?
他一露面  我们就干掉他
Shows his face, we'll take him out.
肯定的
Absolutely.
尸体
A body.
芬奇  乔治的人
Finch, George's men
已经在莱利的公寓楼了
are already at Riley's apartment building.
他肯定知道埃迪的事了
He must know about Eddie.
也就是说他们也在找安妮了
Which means they'll be looking for Annie too.
我们得确认她没在家里
We need to make sure she's not at her place.
芬奇
Finch?
我可以叫弗斯科去
I can call Fusco.
不  没关系
No, that's all right.
好的  我到了再打给你
Yes, I'll call you when I get there.
没关系
It's okay.
我没事的
I'll be fine.
催查车牌那边加急
See if you can put a rush on those plates.
好的
Sure.
只要它们在系统里有记录
If they're in the system,
我要第一时间知道
I want to know as soon as you do.
好的  交给我了
All right. You got it.
舍曼斯基警探
Detective Szymanski.
你又回来工作了  真好
It's good to see you back on active duty.
我考虑过死了算了  但意识到
You know, I thought about dying, but I realized
就凭一个警探的薪水我还死不起
I couldn't afford it on a detective's salary.
你来这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
听说这儿有尸体
Heard there was a body.
这么快
Already?
凶案组可不能浪费时间
Homicide Task Force doesn't mess around.
-什么情况  -车祸
- What you got? - It's a car wreck.
死者是埃迪・梅西
The deceased is Eddie Massey.
不妙啊
Not good.
我听说他爸爸脾气不好
I hear his dad's got a temper.
埃迪喝多了吗
Eddie have too much to drink?
驾驶受干扰  确实
Under the influence, yes.
但不是因为酒精  而是子弹
But not alcohol, hollow points.
侧身中两枪  近距离射击
Two in the side, close range.
枪还在枪套里
Well, his weapon's still holstered.
凶手一定是突然袭击的
Shooter must have taken him by surprise.
他的乘客
His passenger?
看起来是的  安全气囊弹开了
Sounds right, airbag deployed.
只有在前排坐人[散弹枪]的情况下才会弹开
Only goes off if someone's riding shotgun,
不过这次不是散弹枪而是点三八
or in this case, .38 caliber.
如果枪手当时在车里
Well, if the shooter was in the car,
埃迪应该认识他
Eddie probably knew who he was.
瞧瞧我们找到了什么
Let's see what we got here.
今早接过一个匿名电话
Received a call from a blocked number early this morning,
之后还有几个未接电话
and then after that, several missed calls.
-有人在找他  -也许是他爸爸
- Somebody's looking for him. - Probably his dad.
是啊
Yup.
安妮已经走了
Annie's already gone.
有什么线索能查到她去哪里了吗
Anything to tell us where she went?
芬奇
Finch?
我在找  我在找
I'm looking. I'm looking.
有发现吗
Any luck?
还没有
Nothing yet.
他们要说有秘密约会的地方
If they've got a secret meeting place,
那她隐藏得很好
she's hidden it well.
当然
Oh, of course.
别停留太久被逮住
Well, just don't get caught hanging around.
没那打算
I don't intend to.
你联系过我们的警探了么
Did you reach our detectives?
两个都派上了
I got them both on the job.
舍曼斯基警探
Detective Szymanski.
乔治  这位是卡特警探
George, this is Detective Carter.
我听说了你几个月前的事故
I heard about the incident you had a few months ago.
真担心我们会失去你
Feared we might have lost you.
乔治  恐怕要告诉你个坏消息
George, I'm afraid I've got some bad news.
埃迪死了
Eddie's dead.
我知道了
I'm aware.
听到这消息你似乎不怎么难过
You don't seem too upset about the news.
每个人表达悲伤的方式不一样  警探
We all deal with grief differently, Detective.
那你是怎么表达的
How are you dealing with yours?
找出杀害我儿子的凶手  你就会看到了
Find my son's killer, and you'll see.
乔治  你最后一次看到埃迪是什么时候
George, when was the last time you saw Eddie?
昨天
Yesterday.
我们吃过午饭  回到这里
We had lunch, came back here.
知道他昨晚那么晚还在那里干什么
Any idea what he was doing out so late last night
和谁在一起吗
or with whom?
不知道
Couldn't say.
车祸前不久他接过一个电话
He received a call shortly before the crash.
是你打的吗
Was it from you?
有时间纠缠我
You know, instead of badgering me,
你们何不出去找找
shouldn't you be out there trying to find out
杀害我儿子的凶手
who killed my son?
你的手下呢
Where's your crew?
我的什么
My what?
你的儿子刚被枪杀
Well, your son was just gunned down,
可能是敌对帮派干的
maybe by a rival gang.
我以为你会采取点保护措施
I'd expect you to have some protection.
-我能照顾好我自己  -想来也是
- I can take care of myself. - I'm sure.
也许你已经知道凶手是谁了
Or you already know who the shooter is,
你的手下已经在追杀他了
and your boys are out looking for him.
放心吧  警探
Rest assured, Detective,
如果我找到了杀害埃迪的凶手
if I find the person responsible for Eddie's murder,
你们永远都不会知道
you'll never know.
喂
Yep?
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
上帝保佑你
God bless you.
告诉所有人  他们就要出现了
Check in with everybody. They'll show up.
他们一到  就通知我
When they do, I want to know.
里瑟先生  我好像发现了点东西
Mr. Reese, I may have found something.
太好了  芬奇
That's good, Finch,
因为我好像弄丢了点东西
because I may have lost something.
安妮很谨慎  没留下她和莱利
Annie was very careful not to leave any clues
约会地点的线索  不过
as to her and Riley's meeting place, but...
似乎有一个
maybe there is one.
她的电脑桌面是一张她拍的
Her laptop wallpaper is a view of the city
城市景观照
from a photo she took.
好吧
Okay.
根据估测准线
By measuring the alignment,
和照片里主要建筑的相对尺寸
and relative size of the key buildings in the photo,
我能够确定拍摄地点的
I was able to determine the geographical coordinates
地理坐标
of the spot where it was taken.
在海拔15米左右
Approximately 50 feet above sea level.
太好了  你的巫毒术能给出个地址吗
Great, now does any of that voodoo produce an address?
埃克福德街460号
460 Eckford.
还有那是三角定位原理
And it's trigonometry.
我们怎么知道那里跟莱利有关系
How do we know that has anything to do with Riley?
因为
Because...
埃克福德街460号是他档案中的第一个地址
460 Eckford is his first known address.
是他长大的地方
It's where he grew up.
这么说他带她回家了
So he brought her home.
那儿离你只有四个街区
It's only four blocks away from you.
乔治是怎么发现的
How did George find out?
无所谓了  我们必须得离开
It doesn't matter, we gotta go.
我得把你送上火车
I gotta get you on a train and
走得越远越好  安妮
as far away from here as possible, Annie.
-我  -是的
- Me? - Yes.
你是说我们吧  你不走我也不走
You mean us. I'm not leaving without you.
安妮
Annie.
你说想离开这城市
You said you wanted out of the city.
你说我们可以去西部找个开阔的地方
You said we'd find some wide open place out West
一起从头开始
and start over together.
他们在找我
They're looking for me.
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
你不走我也不走  我做不到
I won't do this without you. I can't.
你可以的  安妮  听我说
Yes, you can, Annie. Now listen, okay?
-我准备  安妮  -不不  你听我说
- I'm gonna--Annie. - No, no! You listen to me.
肖恩过世后  你来我们餐厅
After Sean died, you came by the restaurant.
给我电话号码
You gave me your number,
说如果我有任何需要
and you said if I ever needed anything,
尽管找你  记得吗
to just call, you remember?
是的
Yeah.
后来我的热水器坏了
And then my water heater broke.
忽然爆了  水溅得到处都是
Just exploded, water everywhere.
是啊  你给我打了电话
Yeah, and you called.
我以为你早忘了
I didn't think you'd even remember,
但你说你马上就来
but you said you'd be right there,
你真的来了
and you were.
虽然来了也没什么用
Of course you were next to useless,
只是在没过脚的水里乱来一气
splashing around in water up to your ankles.
松松这个  紧紧那个
Loosening this, tightening that.
但你来了  信守了承诺
But you came. You kept your promise,
之后的每一次都是如此
just like you did every time after that.
你总是陪着我
You were there.
我很喜欢
I love that.
知道有你可以信赖  我需要这样
Knowing I can count on you, I need to know that.
我不在乎谁知道了  或者有多危险
So I don't care who knows or how dangerous it is.
没有你我不会走  绝不
I'm not going anywhere without you, not ever.
好吗
Okay?
-好吗  -好吧
- Okay? - Okay.
-我们走  -好的
- Let's get going. - Okay.
-里面是什么  -积蓄
- What's in there? - Savings.
这些钱足够我们去任何地方
It's enough money to get us wherever we need to go.
不
No.
不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no, no!
不如你意了吗
Not what you were expecting?
乔治
George.
以为我不知道你的藏钱处吗
You didn't know I knew about your stash, huh,
以为我不知道你搞上了肖恩的女人吗
or the fact that you were sticking it to Sean's old lady?
你想怎么样
What do you want?
让我儿子起死回生如何
How about my son back?
我很抱歉  乔治
I'm sorry, George,
但埃迪逼得我走投无路
but Eddie didn't give me a choice.
你过会儿可以亲自向他道歉
Well, you can apologize to him yourself in a moment or two.
蹲下
Get down!
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
芬奇  乔治的手下伏击了他们
Finch, George's men tried to ambush them.
莱利带着安妮跑了
Riley's with Annie on the run.
千万小心  里瑟先生
Do be careful, Mr. Reese.
多谢提醒  芬奇
Thanks for the tip, Finch.
里瑟先生  你没事吧
Mr. Reese, is everything all right?
死不了
I'll survive.
-安妮和莱利怎么样了  -不太确定
- What about Annie and Riley? - I'm not sure.
埃迪车上采集到的指纹是莱利・卡瓦诺的
Prints taken off Eddie's car belong to Riley Cavanaugh,
梅西最顶级的执刑人之一
One of Massey's top enforcers.
难怪乔治一点都不惊恐
Oh, no wonder George wasn't sweating.
他是在找自己的手下
He was looking for one of his own.
大楼的一名住户说
One of the building tenants
她看到了一个符合卡瓦诺特征的人
said she saw a guy matching Cavanaugh's description,
带着个女人离开了大楼  可能是人质
leaving the building with a woman, could be a hostage.
我们知道他什么情况
What do we know about him?
他是过去两年三起黑帮袭击案的嫌犯
He's a suspect in three mob-related hits over the past two years.
冷血杀手一个
He's a stone-cold killer.
我们要把他找出来  绳之以法
We gotta find him, take him down.
我是舍曼斯基
Szymanski.
行  明白  好的
Yeah, we got it. Okay.
就这个
That's the stuff.
-生日快乐  -你怎么知道的
- Happy birthday. - How did you know?
在重新考虑保护是否该莱利吗
Reconsidering your decision to protect Riley?
不是  在想是否该弄件新衬衫
No, just thinking I should grab a new shirt.
他冲你开枪了  约翰
He shot you, John.
他不是有心的
It wasn't personal.
我们应该集中精力解决更紧迫的问题
Maybe we should focus on the more pressing issue
先找到他们
of finding them.
怎么样  警探
Yes, Detective?
你家那位恐怖的高酷帅先生
Your partner, Mr. Tall Dark And Fearsome
-可真把梅西逼急了  -什么意思
- really got Massey steamed. - Meaning what?
意思是他在道上悬赏追杀卡瓦诺跟那妞儿
Meaning he put a bounty on Cavanaugh and the broad.
-多少钱  -一百万
- How much? - A million.
有消息通知我
Keep me informed.
如果弗斯科警探的消息没错
If Detective Fusco is correct,
安妮和莱利会被全城的雇佣杀手追杀
Annie and Riley will have every hired gun in the city looking for them.
乔治没那个实力
George is too small of a fish
闹这么大动静
to pull off a move like this.
这得要向全城放话
He'll need to get the word out city-wide.
那他会向谁寻求这种帮助呢
And who would he reach out to for that kind of help?
你想想办法呗
See what you can do.
你去哪儿
Where are you going?
乔治把莱利准备重新生活的钱拿走了
George took the money Riley was gonna use to start over.
他们离城前  他需要弄到钱
He'll need to get more before they leave town.
我大概知道他们会去哪儿
I think I know where they might go.
你好  卡特
Hello, Carter.
莱利・卡瓦诺  这就是你要保护的人
Riley Cavanaugh? That's who you're protecting?
他在保护一名无辜的女人
He's protecting an innocent woman.
你为什么不早点告诉我
Why didn't you tell me this earlier?
因为我需要你去审问乔治・梅西
Because I needed you to question George Massey.
你是说分散他的注意力
You mean distract him.
-那女人呢  -安妮・德莱尼
- What about the woman? - Annie Delaney.
到目前为止  莱利最能保护她
Right now, Riley's her best protection.
好吧  舍曼斯基也想抓那家伙
Yeah, well, Szymanski's also looking to take this guy down.
所以我要你和他待在一起
Which is exactly why I need you to stay with him,
阻止此事发生
to make sure that doesn't happen.
你想让我扰乱谋杀案调查
You want me to derail a homicide investigation.
还有别的吩咐吗
Anything else?
再联系
I'll be in touch.
手头就这么多
This is all I have on hand.
需要的话我可以去银行
I can go to the bank if you need more.
不用了阿里  已经很好了
No Al. This is great.
我会都还给你  我保证
I'll pay you back every cent, I promise.
安妮  有人早前来过
Annie, some men came by earlier,
乔治的手下  问起你
George's men, asking for you.
你怎么说的
What did you say?
实话实说  我没见到你
The truth. I hadn't seen you.
真不知道该怎么谢你  阿里
I don't know how to thank you, Al,
谢谢你为我做的一切
everything you've done for me.
安妮  你真的没事吗
Annie, are you sure you're okay?
是的  别担心
Yeah, don't worry.
谢谢你
And thank you.
芬奇  有人想抓
Finch, someone's trying to collect the bounty
莱利和安妮领赏
on Riley and Annie.
我们得走了
We gotta go!
走错路了  几位
Wrong way, guys.
芬奇  我找到莱利和安妮了
Finch, I found Riley and Annie,
赏金猎人也找到他们了
and so have the bounty hunters.
我们的老朋友那边有进展吗
Any luck with our old friend?
稍后给你消息
I'll have an answer for you shortly.
开门
The gate.
你们下去吧
You guys can go.
似乎你让我处于劣势了
So I'm afraid you have me at a disadvantage,
克灵先生  是吧
Mr. Crane, is it?
显然你知道我的一些事
You obviously know something about me,
但我对你一无所知
but I know nothing about you.
我的同事救过一个
The man I work with saved the life
和你关系密切的人  查理・伯顿
of someone close to you, Charlie Burton.
原来你是老大
So you're the boss.
那我似乎
I suppose I, uh--
我应该感谢你救了我一命
I...should thank you for saving my life,
以及享受目前这待遇
as well as my current accommodations.
我相信你没让自己闲着  以利亚先生
I trust you're keeping yourself busy, Mr. Elias.
显然你对这座城市犯罪集团的控制
Certainly your control of the city's criminal enterprises
未有稍减
appears undiminished.
物质方面都被剥夺了
Well, being stripped of all possessions
倒免去了不少纷扰
eliminates a lot of distractions.
我有充足的时间读书  思考  下棋
I've got time to read, to think, to play chess.
不过你懂的  找个势均力敌的对手
Though, you know, finding a worthy opponent
颇有点难度
has been a little challenging.
你找我什么事
What brings you to see me?
有位小头目的事需要你帮忙
We need help with a minor boss
他的帮派目前并没有归顺你
whose organization may not be under your control yet.
乔治・梅西
George Massey.
我听说他儿子的事了
I heard about his son.
-我们约翰干的吗  -不  他自己手下人干的
- Our friend John's handiwork? - No, one of his own men,
那人现在受我们保护
fallen under our protection now.
梅西悬赏一百万追杀他以及
Massey's put a million-dollar bounty on him
和跟他一起的女人
and the woman he's with.
是啊  真土豪啊
Ah, yes. So flashy.
梅西这种老东西  永远都不懂
Relics like Massey, they never learn.
真正的大玩家
There's so much more to be gained
会避开关注  隐身幕后
by staying out of the limelight, in the background.
这种人才是真正需要提防的
Those are the people you have to watch out for.
正是
Indeed.
我们认为梅西会向这种人寻求帮助
We thought he might reach out to such a man for help.
如果真的如此  我们希望能说服你
If so, we hoped we could convince you
拒绝支持
to withhold your assistance.
你想让我叫停梅西的狩猎派对吗
So you want me to shut down Massey's little hunting party?
我似乎确实欠了你一条命
Well, I suppose I do owe you something for saving my life.
即便如此  凡事都有代价
Even so, everything does come with a cost.
我想也是
I assumed there would be.
你想要什么
What is it you want?
我说过了  我对物质方面没什么需求
Well, as I said, I have no need of possessions.
列车将在五分钟后由35号站台出发
Will be leaving from track 35 in approximately five minutes.
我去买票  好吗
I'm gonna go get some tickets, okay?
-我跟你一起去  -不不  你留在这
- I'll go with you. - No, no. Just stay here.
-里瑟先生  -说吧  芬奇
- Mr. Reese? - Go ahead, Finch.
赏金猎人的问题已经基本解决了
I believe our bounty hunter problem has been neutralized.
你真说服以利亚出手了
You actually got Elias to help yourself.
是的  他禁了乔治的悬赏
Yes, he's made George's bounty forbidden fruit.
谁敢动手  就得向他交待
Anyone going after it will have to answer to him.
温馨提示  请不要将您的随身物品
As a reminder, please do not leave your bags--
看来还有人没收到消息啊  芬奇
Looks like someone didn't get the message, Finch,
他还想着赚这钱呢
and he's still gonna try to collect.
那边
Over there!
里瑟先生  发生了什么事
Mr. Reese, what's happening?
有个赏金猎人在追杀莱利
One of the bounty hunters is going after Riley.
他抓住莱利了吗
Did he get to him?
没有  那赏金猎人抓了安妮
No, the bounty hunter took Annie.
她不见了
She's gone.
跟我来
Follow me!
里瑟先生  你在哪儿
Mr. Reese, where are you?
跟踪莱利  警察盯上他了
Following Riley. Police spotted him.
但你刚才说安妮被抓走了
But I thought you said that Annie had been taken!
没错
I did.
那为什么还在莱利身上浪费时间
Then why are you wasting time on Riley?
他是个杀手  他只是
He's a killer. He's just...
错误代码
bad code.
-错误什么  -当我没说
- Bad what? - Forget it.
莱利目前所做的一切都是为了保护安妮
Everything Riley's done so far is to protect Annie.
赏金猎人最终会把她交给乔治
The bounty hunter still has to deliver her to George,
所以莱利会去那里
so that's where Riley's headed.
怎么样  警探
Yes, Detective?
梅西行动了
Yeah, Massey's on the move.
知道他去了哪里吗
Do you know where he was headed?
不知道  他肯定是从后门溜出去的
No, he must have slipped out the back.
好的  他回来就给我电话
Okay, call me if he returns.
你他妈是谁
Who the hell are you?
一个知道你在对抗什么的人
Someone who knows what you're up against.
是吗  你知道什么
Yeah? What do you know?
我知道你杀埃迪是为了救安妮
I know you shot Eddie to save Annie.
还知道你自从她丈夫被杀之后
And I know you've been protecting her
就一直在保护她
since her husband was killed.
俄罗斯人干的  是吗
Russians, right?
是的
That's right.
真奇怪  居然在他还欠着一大笔钱时杀了他
Strange they'd kill him when he still owed them so much money
还把他的尸体扔在自己的地盘
and then leave his body in their own territory.
太奇怪了
It's very strange,
除非俄罗斯人根本没杀肖恩
unless maybe the Russians didn't kill Sean.
也许另有他人
Maybe it was someone else,
某个想嫁祸给他们的人
someone who wanted to make it look like they did.
专业的人  比如你
A professional. Someone like you.
肖恩偷藏钱  拿去还给俄罗斯人
Sean was skimming to pay back the Russians.
乔治发现了  让人办了他
George caught him and had him whacked.
乔治让人杀了他
George had him killed,
但下手的人  是你
But the hit-- it was you.
杀了肖恩后  乔治让我监视安妮
After Sean, George had me keep tabs on Annie.
他对她有意思
He had a thing for her.
他同时希望她不要问太多问题
He also wanted to make sure she didn't ask too many questions.
但你却爱上了她
But you fell for her instead,
乔治发现了
and George found out.
安妮是无辜的
Annie doesn't deserve any of this.
她只是想远走高飞  重新开始
She just wants to get away from here and start over.
但她不知道肖恩的事
But she doesn't know about Sean.
你真以为这事能就此了结吗
Do you really think you can run away from that?
不
No.
我知道自己什么货色
I know what I am.
但我也知道
But I also know that
她是我生命中最美好的
she's the best thing that's ever happened to me,
我会不惜一切代价救她
and I will do whatever I gotta do to save her.
如果你就这样贸贸然跑去找乔治
Well, if you go charging in at George half-cocked,
还没救到她  你自己就死了
you'll be dead before you can even do her any good.
走  我们得快
Come on, we need to move.
走
Come on.
是死胡同
It's a dead end.
现在呢
What now?
尽力而为
We consider our options.
朝警察开枪绝对不行
Shooting at cops isn't one of them.
你有更好的主意  说来听听
You got a better idea, let's hear it.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
-好的  -卡特
- Yes. - Carter.
情况如何  警探
How's it going, Detective?
舍曼斯基对那杀手布下了搜索网
Szymanski's got a dragnet out for your hit man.
我建议你暂时离远点儿
I suggest you steer clear for a while.
那可有点困难
Well, that's gonna be a little difficult.
别说你正和他在一起
Don't tell me you're with him.
好吧  我不说  但我还是需要你的帮助
Okay, I won't, but I still need your help.
约翰  这家伙杀了埃迪・梅西
John, this guy killed Eddie Massey.
埃迪准备杀掉他和一名无辜的女人
Eddie was gonna kill him and an innocent woman.
我相信地检官会予以考虑的
Well, I'm sure the DA will take that into consideration.
这不是在帮莱利
This isn't about helping Riley,
而是在救安妮
it's about saving Annie.
如果我错了
Look, if I'm wrong...
我会亲手把他交给你
I'll turn him in to you myself.
有线索了
I got a tip!
我有线人看见卡瓦诺出现在43街和10街交叉处
One of my CIs saw Cavanaugh over near 43rd and 10th.
-调人过去  快  -出发
- Call it in. Come on. - Let's go.
43街和10街交叉处有目击报告
We got a sighting at 43rd and 10th.
你居然还掌握着一名警探
You got a detective in your pocket?
谈不上是掌握
More like on my back.
43街和10街交叉处发现嫌犯
Suspect reported near 43rd and 10th.
走吧
Let's go.
芬奇  我找到莱利了  现在去找安妮
Finch, I've got Riley. We're going to get Annie.
她不在乔治的酒吧
Well, you won't find her at George's pub.
弗斯科警探说他匆忙离开了
Detective Fusco said he left in a hurry.
乔治会把安妮带到哪里去
Where would George take Annie?
-珍珠那儿  -什么
- The Pearl. - The what?
翡翠珍珠  乔治开的夜店
The Emerald Pearl's a nightclub that George owned.
之前倒闭了  不过他留着  用于其他业务
It went under, but he kept it for--uh, for other business.
比如处理尸体
Like making bodies disappear.
你知道那地方
You know this place?
-知道  -走吧
- Yeah. - Let's go.
她男朋友呢
What about her boyfriend?
见他时  他正在朝门外跑
Last I saw, he was running for the door.
我怎么一点也不吃惊呢
Why am I not surprised?
没关系
That's okay.
我很快就会逮住那个懦夫
I'm gonna catch up with that coward soon enough.
我现在可以拿到钱了吧
So I suppose I'll be taking my money now.
一百万是买两个人的
The million was for the both of them.
一半也可以
I'll settle for half,
除非你觉得不合理
unless you think that's unreasonable.
管它呢  我现在心情很好
What the hell, I'm in a good mood.
科里  给他钱
Corey, get this guy his money.
你干什么呢
What do you think you're doing?
给你们老大送礼
Bringing your boss a present.
我应该可以领到报酬了
I believe I'm due a reward.
原本事情不至于此  对吧
You know that none of this needed to happen, right?
我想帮你  安妮
I wanted to help you, Annie.
而我得到了什么
And what did I get?
感谢  不
Gratitude? No.
侮辱
Insults!
把肖恩的事归罪于我
Blame for Sean.
说实话  这点你还真对了
Oh, to tell the truth, you were right on that score.
肖恩不仅是个堕落的赌鬼
You see, Sean was not only a degenerate gambler,
他还是个小偷
he was also a thief.
我给了他应得的报应
I gave him what he deserved.
你还有脸说莱利是懦夫
And you call Riley a coward.
莱利  是啊
Riley. Yeah.
莱利跟你说过吗
Did Riley ever tell you--?
不  当然没有
No, of course not.
说什么
Tell me what?
肖恩到底怎么了
What really happened to Sean.
放她走  乔治
Let her go, George.
瞧瞧
Well, look at that.
谁敢动一下  我先毙了你
Anybody moves, I'm shooting you first.
见到你真好  孩子
Hey, good to see you, kid.
你可为我省了50万
Yeah, you know, you just saved me 500 grand.
你还好吗  安妮
Are you okay, Annie?
她没事
Oh, she's fine.
我们刚刚正在谈肖恩呢
We were just having a little conversation about Sean.
放她走  乔治
Let her go, George.
-别动  -他没法同时向我们两个开枪
- Don't. - He can't shoot both of us.
也没那必要
He won't have to.
带上安妮  去厨房  我来掩护
Take Annie, go for the kitchen, I'll cover you.
不  你离得更近
No! You're closer.
带她离开
Get her out of here.
走  照顾好安妮
Go! Take care of Annie!
-我们得走了  -莱利不走我也不走
- We have to move. - I'm not leaving without Riley.
安妮  走
Annie, go.
走  没事的
Go, it's okay.
我会过去的
I will be right there.
快走
Go!
我就不该派埃迪去
I never should have sent Eddie.
我应该亲手杀了你
I should have killed you myself.
她说得很对
She was right, you know.
没人会想念我们的
No one's gonna miss either one of us.
莱利呢
Riley?
-我们不能抛下他  -我不会的
- We can't leave him. - I'm not.
带她离开
Get her out here.
安妮  这是莱利身上的
Annie, Riley had this on him.
只有一张吗
Just the one?
原来他根本没打算来
So he wasn't coming after all.
他知道如果他来了  会连累你
He knew you'd always be looking over your shoulder if he did.
我还一直骗自己  以为我能改变他
I was fooling myself to think I could change him.
你做到了
But you did.
你给了他力量
You gave him the strength
去摆脱自己原来的生活
to walk away from the only life he knew,
变得更好
to be better.
他说你是他生命中最美好的
He said you were the best thing that ever happened to him.
谢谢
Thank you.
祝你好运
Good luck.
? Once I wanted to be the greatest ?
她要去哪
Where's she headed?
-新墨西哥州  -开阔的地方
- New Mexico. - A wide open place.
? No wind or waterfall could stop me ?
之前  你说的"错误代码"是什么意思
Earlier, what did you mean when you said, "bad code"?
意思是设计缺陷
It means a flawed design.
这术语适用于机器  不适用于人类
The term applies to machines, not to people.
人类有能力改变  进化
We have the ability to change, evolve.
即使是杀手
Even killers.
那个
So...
你还没告诉我以利亚
you never did tell me what Elias wanted
? Leave no trace of grace ?
撤销悬赏的条件
for calling off the bounty.
? Just in your honor ?
? Once I wanted to be the greatest ?
? Two faced sad little rock ?
? When things I couldn't explain ?
? Any feeling ?
钱可以归你
You can have the money.
我不是为钱而来
I'm not here for the money.